CHRIS ARSENAULT

chrisstanarsenault@gmail.com

🔾 www.chrisarsenault.dev 📞 647-920-0506

? Toronto Ontario

O chrisstanarsenault

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

Lighthouse Labs Oct. 2018 to Jan. 2019 Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

A full stack developer from Toronto, Ontario, with a passion for all things front-end. I am extremely motivated and driven to grow my knowledge and skills in web development. With my many years working in the hospitality district, I have substantial experience of working as a team, as well as team building. I am excited to bring my eager attitude and past team experience into an innovative environment.

PROJECTS

DRAWANGO

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/drawango

A drawing/guessing party game built to learn to work further with React and Canvas in a realtime drawing environment.

TechStacks: React, CSS/SASS, Express, NodeJS, Websockets

JUNGLE APP

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/jungle-rails An e-commerce Rails app built for learning Rails

TechStacks: Ruby, Rails, Bootstrap, CSS/SASS, PG, Active Record

CHATTY APP

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/chatty-app Simple single page chat app built with React and Websockets TechStacks: React, CSS/SASS, Express, NodeJS, JS, Websockets

HOOKEAI POKE

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/hookeai-poke

A food ordering and pickup service for the fictitious restaurant 'Hookeai Pookeai'

TechStacks: HTML, CSS/SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Express, NodeJS, EJS, PostSQL, Knex, AJAX, Twilio

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Ruby

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES, ENVIRONMENTS: NodeJS, React, AJAX, Express, Knex, JQuery, Bootstrap, Rails, Websockets/Socket.io, Vue DATABASES, SYSTEMS, CMS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Git, WordPress

EMPLOYMENT

416 MEDIA

WordPress Developer (freelance)

Toronto, Ontario Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2019

Toronto, ON

Mar. 2019 to Current

- data entry, migrating content from old client site to new updated site
- created basic html tables to help organize some of the information
- custom css work to fix with some of the formatting and aesthetic
- connected GoogleMap API and billing to new account

WORLD LEGAL SUMMIT

WordPress Developer

- general maintenance of the pre-existing website
- customize layouts as per client's needs
- pluain maintenance which increased speed and search optimization. Brought PageSpeed score from initial 35% to 74%
- worked directly with each city host (approx 30-40) clients to add new updates and revisions to their individual event page (adding logos, documents, location details, speaker information, etc)
- implementing any new requested features or software needs such as:
 - live streaming capabilities for each host location
 - set up Zendesk and created a custom theme for a knowledge base and community section
 - integrated a method to connect the Mailchimp account with separate GoogleSheets to collect signup information for each host, when interested parties requested an invite to their cities Summit.

TORONTO LAWN TENNIS CLUB

Member Services Supervisor

- booking tennis/squash courts for members
- giving tours to new perspective members
- answering all inquiries
- being knowledgeable and up-to-date on all club related news and events
- training all new front desk staff
- assisting with any requests from other departments

Toronto, Ontario June 2013 to Oct. 2018